Anil Kumar

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Well-qualified Full Stack Developer familiar with wide range of programming utilities and languages. Knowledgeable of backend and frontend development requirements. Handles any part of process with ease. Collaborative team player with excellent technical abilities offering 1.5 years of related experience.

WORK HISTORY

Altorum Leren Pvt. Ltd. - Full Stack Developer (MEAN)

Bangalore, India 01/2022 - Current

• Alfinity Marketplace (Feb 2022 - July 2022)

Key role in developing IoT products marketplace at Altorum Leren Pvt. Ltd. Created GraphQL APIs, managed authentication, registration, profiles, orders, banking, and invoices. Result: User-friendly platform connecting customers to diverse IoT devices with ease. Streamlined experience for exploration, purchase, and device management.

Tech Stack: Angular 13, NodeJs, Express.Js, GraphQL, MongoDB, RxJs, Tailwind, SCSS, HTML5.

• Toyota Chassis Verification System (July 2022 - Aug 2022)
Developed an Angular and Node.js application for real-time
verification of Toyota vehicle chassis numbers during automated
assembly. The app compares scanned barcodes with cameradetected numbers, providing immediate status updates. It interacts
with Toyota's server, generates alarms for errors, and includes a
history feature for past chassis statuses.

Tech Stack: Angular 13, NodeJs, WebSocket, Socket.IO, TypeScript, Tailwind, SCSS, HTML5

• Alfinity Cloud (Aug 2022 - Nov 2022)

Full stack developer at Altorum Leren Pvt. Ltd., contributed to Alfinity Cloud, a multi-tenant architecture product. Designed interactive graphs, charts, and maps for live data display on a dynamic dashboard. Developed ticket/case management, three-level user login system, and user profile management. Integrated

Bangalore, India 560034 8696267477 anillakhlan2107@gmail.com

SKILLS

- Angular v13, Angular Material
- Node.Js,Express.Js
- JavaScript, TypeScript
- Postresql, mySQL, MongoDB, Redis, InfluxDB
- TypeORM, Mongoose, Raw Queries
- HTML5, CSS, SCSS, Tailwind, Bootstrap
- Reactive Programming (RxJs)
- REST API, GraphQL
- Strapi Content Management
- · Git, Postman, Firebase
- WebSocket, MQTT, Modbus
- C++, Industrial Routers(Teltonika)

EDUCATION

2022

National Institute of Technology (NIT), Patna Patna

Bachelor of Technology:

Electrical Engineering CGPA: 8.01

2017

B.L.G Sr. sec. school,
Rampura (RBSE))
Rampura, Churu (Rajasthan)

Intermediate: PCM Percentage: 80.60%

live plant data for a comprehensive, user-friendly experience.

Tech Stack: Angular 13, RxJs, Tailwind, SCSS, HTML5, TypeScript, Node.js, Express.js, Postgresql, MongoDB, Influx DB, Redis, TypeORM, Mongoose

• Delopt (Dec 2022- Jan 2023):

Its an client based project which includes dashboard for counting passengers. And Some alarm operation.

Tech Stack: Angular 13, Node.Js, MongoDB, RxJs, C++, cross compilation Embedded Device.

 Modbus TCP Data Collection & MQTT Integration (Jan 20223- Mar 2023):

Modbus TCP for data collection, MQTT integration for real-time transmission, local SQLite storage for network resilience. Cross-compiled for RUT200, ensuring reliable data collection and transmission.

Tech Stack: C++, MQTT, Modbus TCP, Javascript, Websocket. HTML5, CSS

 Bluetooth-based Eye Sensor Data Alert System (March 2023- May 2023):

Tracks museum movement via Bluetooth, sends MQTT alerts for email & SMS on detection. Prompt response & artifact protection ensured with comprehensive data.

Tech Stack: Nodejs, MQTT, Twillio (SMS), SendGrid (Mail), C++

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Got 2nd Prize in Chakravyuh Event In NIT Patna Tech-fest.
- Received Appreciation Letter in Altorum Leren on Completing Delopt Client Project.

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

- LinkedIn www.linkedin.com/in/anilkumar2107/
- GitHub github.com/anillakhlan21
- Portfolio portfolio-a17d6.web.app/

LANGUAGES

Hindi C2 English B2

Proficient Upper Intermediate

2015

B.L.G Sr. sec. school,
Rampura (RBSE)
Rampura, Churu (Rajasthan)

Matriculation

Percentage: 89.83%